If adventure has a name... it must be Indiana Jones.
Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom is a adventure,
action film directed by Steven Spielberg.
After arriving in India, Indiana Jones is asked by a
desperate village to find a mystical stone.
He agrees – and stumbles upon a secret cult plotting a
terrible plan in the catacombs of an ancient palace.
Indiana Jones, played by Harrison Ford.
Willie Scott, played by Kate Capshaw.
Short Round, played by Ke Huy Quan.
Mola Ram, played by Amrish Puri.
Chattar Lal, played by Roshan Seth.
Phillip Blumburtt, played by Philip Stone.
Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom is a 1984 American action-adventure film directed by Steven
Spielberg from a script by Willard Huyck and Gloria Katz, based on a story by George Lucas.
It is the second installment in the Indiana Jones film series and
a standalone prequel to Raiders of the Lost Ark.
The film stars Harrison Ford, who reprises his role as the titular character.
Kate Capshaw, Amrish Puri, Roshan Seth, Philip Stone and Ke Huy
Quan, in his film debut, star in supporting roles.
Set in 1935, in the film, after arriving in British India, Indiana Jones is asked by desperate villagers to find a mystical stone and rescue their
children from a Thuggee cult to all appearances practicing child slavery, black magic and ritual human sacrifice in honor of the demon Kali.
Not wishing to feature the Nazis as the villains again, executive producer and
story writer George Lucas decided to regard this film as a prequel.
Three plot devices were rejected before Lucas wrote a film
treatment that resembled the final storyline.
As Lawrence Kasdan, Lucas's collaborator on Raiders of the Lost Ark, turned down the offer to write the script, Willard Huyck and
Gloria Katz, who had previously worked with Lucas on American Graffiti (1973), were hired as his replacements.
Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom was released on May 23, 1984, to financial success,
grossing $333.1 million worldwide, making it the highest-grossing film of 1984.
Initial critical reviews were mixed, with criticism aimed at its strong violence, as well as
some of its darker story elements, and controversy over its portrayal of India.
Critical opinion has improved since 1984, citing the
film's intensity and imagination.
In response to some of the more violent sequences in the film, and with similar complaints about the Spielberg-produced Gremlins (which released two weeks later), Spielberg
suggested that the Motion Picture Association of America (MPAA) alter its rating system, which it did within two months of the film's release, creating a new PG-13 rating.
Temple of Doom was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Original
Score and won the Academy Award for Best Visual Effects.
A third film, Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade, followed in 1989.
The film explores themes of treasure, skeleton, wind, elephant, heart.